<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<component type="desktop-application">
  <id>de.bforartists.Bforartists</id>
  
  <name>Bforartists</name>
  <summary>A complete, free and opensource 3D suite</summary>
  
  <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
  <project_license>GPL-3.0</project_license>


  <developer id="tld.vendor">
    <name>Mahid Sheikh</name>
  </developer>


  <branding>
    <color type="primary" scheme_preference="light">#9ed2ff</color>
    <color type="primary" scheme_preference="dark">#2a577e</color>
  </branding>
  
  <description>
    <p>
     Bforartists is a complete, free and opensource 3D suite to create CG content. It offers you the full 3D art pipeline to create game graphics, pre-rendered movies and stills. From modeling, sculpting, texturing, rigging, animation, rendering, up to post processing. 
    </p>
  </description>
  <url type="homepage">https://www.bforartists.de/</url>
  <url type="help">https://www.bforartists.de/get-involved//</url>
  <url type="bugtracker">https://github.com/flathub/de.bforartists.Bforartists/issues</url>
  <launchable type="desktop-id">de.bforartists.Bforartists.desktop</launchable>
  <screenshots>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <image>https://www.bforartists.de/wp-content/uploads/2023/11/Bforartists-Splashscreen-4.0.1-Large.jpg</image>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <image>https://www.bforartists.de/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/modelingbfa2-1024x619.jpg</image>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <image>https://www.bforartists.de/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/sculptingbfa2.jpg</image>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <image>https://www.bforartists.de/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/animationbfa2.jpg</image>
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>
  <content_rating type="oars-1.1"/>
  <releases>
    <release version="4.1.0" date="2024-04-01"/>
    <release version="4.0.2" date="2023-12-12"/>
    <release version="4.0.1" date="2023-11-19">
      <description>
        <p>Enhancements:</p>
          <ul>
            <li>This version comes with a new Presentation addon, a Shader Node kit for the Asset Browser and procedural materials, and general maintenance with all the latest features, stability, and updates from Blender with all our additional love from us.

            This version has an additional 150 tasks and bug fixes with everything from Blender 4.0.0, 4.0.1 and 4.1.0 development.</li>
          </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="3.6.2" date="2023-08-28">
      <description>
        <p>Enhancements:</p>
          <ul>
            <li>Bforartists 3 Version 3.6.2 is maintenance and bugfix release. This release comes with stability, updates and the latest from Blender, with additional love from us.

            This version has and additional 21 tasks and bug fixes from us everything from Blender 3.6.2 and 4.0.0 development.</li>
          </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="3.6.1" date="2023-07-05">
      <description>
        <p>Enhancements:</p>
          <ul>
            <li>Bforartists 3 Version 3.6.1 is maintenance and bugfix release. This one comes with the changes from Blender 3.6.1 with the usual updating and changes to keep Bforartists consistent and compatible with the latest from Blender.

            This version comes with 30 tasks and additional bug fixes from us with the updates and features from Blender 3.6.1 and 4.0.0 development.</li>
          </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="3.6.0" date="2023-06-04">
      <description>
        <p>Enhancements:</p>
          <ul>
            <li>Bforartists 3 Version 3.6.0 is maintenance and bug fix release. It also comes with a special "add as instance" toggle for the Asset Browser. This build is about Blender 3.6.0 feature set with the usual updating and changes to keep this consistent and compatible with the latest.

            This version comes with 50 tasks and bug fixes from us with the additional updates and features from Blender 3.6.0 and 4.0.0 development.</li>
          </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
  </releases>
</component>
