<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<component type="desktop-application">
  <id>de.bforartists.Bforartists</id>
  
  <name>Bforartists</name>
  <summary>Blender but with UX for artists</summary>
  
  <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
  <project_license>GPL-3.0</project_license>


  <developer id="tld.vendor">
    <name>Bforartists</name>
  </developer>


  <branding>
    <color type="primary" scheme_preference="light">#9ed2ff</color>
    <color type="primary" scheme_preference="dark">#2a577e</color>
  </branding>
  
  <description>
    <p>
      Bforartists is a complete, free and opensource 3D suite to create CG content. It offers you the full 3D art pipeline to create game graphics, pre-rendered movies and stills. From modeling, sculpting, texturing, rigging, animation, rendering, up to post processing. 

      Bforartists gives the full power of Blender but with a nicer UI and user experience. Keyboard-only features are now available through the UI, nodes are given proper descriptions, icons are colored to make things easier to find. Everything is tailored for the user experience.
    </p>
  </description>
  <url type="homepage">https://www.bforartists.de/</url>
  <url type="help">https://www.bforartists.de/get-involved/</url>
  <url type="bugtracker">https://github.com/Bforartists/Bforartists/issues/</url>
  <launchable type="desktop-id">de.bforartists.Bforartists.desktop</launchable>
  <screenshots>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/flathub/de.bforartists.Bforartists/cfe22a87c58322a526d642d2599c1a9cde2fbff3/screenshots/app-window.png</image>
      <caption>Bforartists window</caption>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <image>https://www.bforartists.de/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Belzunze_Splashscreen_Competition_Bforartists_4.1.0.jpg</image>
      <caption>Bforartists splash by Belzunze</caption> 
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>
  <content_rating type="oars-1.1"/>
  <releases>
    <release version="4.2.2" date="2024-08-29">
      <description></description>
    </release>
    <release version="4.2.0" date="2024-07-30">
      <description>
        <ul>
            <li>This release has a new fresh set of features including Brush Assets, Grease Pencil 3.0 with Geometry Nodes compatibility, EEVEE 2.0, Multi-pass AOV's in the Viewport Compositor, and offline and online extensions love! With another 151 task and features added to everything from the latest from Blender 4.2.0 and 4.3.0 Alpha (main branch) to the date.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="4.1.1" date="2024-04-23">
      <description>
        <ul>
            <li>This release has a new feature to assign Collection Exporters for batch exports and another 24 task and features added to everything from the latest from Blender 4.1.1 and 4.2.0 Alpha to the date.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="4.1.0" date="2024-04-01">
      <description>
        <p>Enhancements:</p>
          <ul>
            <li>This release has a new feature called the 3D Sequencer, where you can use scene strips as shots in a "pinned" video sequencer timeline to change the 3D View scene contents, camera, and animation dynamically - also with a new Power User Tools addon and another 123 task and features added to everything from the latest from Blender 4.1.0 and 4.2.0 Alpha to the date.</li>
          </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="4.0.2" date="2023-12-12"/>
    <release version="4.0.1" date="2023-11-19">
      <description>
        <p>Enhancements:</p>
          <ul>
            <li>This version comes with a new Presentation addon, a Shader Node kit for the Asset Browser and procedural materials, and general maintenance with all the latest features, stability, and updates from Blender with all our additional love from us.

            This version has an additional 150 tasks and bug fixes with everything from Blender 4.0.0, 4.0.1 and 4.1.0 development.</li>
          </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="3.6.2" date="2023-08-28">
      <description>
        <p>Enhancements:</p>
          <ul>
            <li>Bforartists 3 Version 3.6.2 is maintenance and bugfix release. This release comes with stability, updates and the latest from Blender, with additional love from us.

            This version has and additional 21 tasks and bug fixes from us everything from Blender 3.6.2 and 4.0.0 development.</li>
          </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="3.6.1" date="2023-07-05">
      <description>
        <p>Enhancements:</p>
          <ul>
            <li>Bforartists 3 Version 3.6.1 is maintenance and bugfix release. This one comes with the changes from Blender 3.6.1 with the usual updating and changes to keep Bforartists consistent and compatible with the latest from Blender.

            This version comes with 30 tasks and additional bug fixes from us with the updates and features from Blender 3.6.1 and 4.0.0 development.</li>
          </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="3.6.0" date="2023-06-04">
      <description>
        <p>Enhancements:</p>
          <ul>
            <li>Bforartists 3 Version 3.6.0 is maintenance and bug fix release. It also comes with a special "add as instance" toggle for the Asset Browser. This build is about Blender 3.6.0 feature set with the usual updating and changes to keep this consistent and compatible with the latest.

            This version comes with 50 tasks and bug fixes from us with the additional updates and features from Blender 3.6.0 and 4.0.0 development.</li>
          </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
  </releases>
</component>
